Nasiru Hammed A.

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

About me

I am passionate about crafting captivating frontend and backend products that offer exceptional user experiences. With a strong affinity for technology and design, I take delight in creating beautiful and engaging solutions.

Beyond my technical interests, I have a keen enthusiasm for education, history, and fitness. These diverse passions inspire me to continuously learn and explore new horizons, both inside and outside of the tech world.

Contact

Address

Lagos State, Nigeria

Phone

+234(0)9082716040

E-mail

nasaces360@gmail.com

Skills

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

React JS

typescript

GraphQL

Git

GitHub

Nodeis

Response Design

Bootstrap

Soft skills

Critical thinking,

Design development,

Time management,

Strong verbal and written communicator

Work History

03. 2023-03. 2023

Open-source contributions

Palisadoes Foundation

- I worked on Talawa project, a project designed to manage communities such as churches, mosques, and clubs. Specifically, I contributed to the development of the admin app using React and TypeScript, and also worked on the Node.js and GraphQL API. One of my notable contributions was creating a feature that allows users to preview their passwords before logging in, which helps prevent errors and save time.
- In addition, I wrote Jest tests to ensure the code meets the Talawa project's code coverage standard of 90%. I also optimized the navbar by aligning the navigation items to the center, which improved the user experience by eliminating white space and making the navbar responsive across all screen sizes.
- This project helped me deepen my understanding of my core tech stack, which includes TypeScript and React, and also gave me the opportunity to learn and work with GraphQL. Throughout the project, I utilized Git and GitHub extensively to contribute effectively to the project.
- I played an active role in engaging with the opensource community by actively participating in discussions, forums, and mailing lists. Through sharing my knowledge, providing assistance to fellow developers, and engaging in productive conversations, I actively contributed to fostering a supportive and collaborative environment within the community.

Languages



Interests

Volunteering Sports and fitness Traveling Reading Swimming

Work History

08. 2022-12. 2022 Web Development internTech Accent Creatives, Lagos, Nigeria

- Write custom Html CSS and JavaScript for existing websites and application.
- Design recommends and pitch improvements to new and existing features.
- systems. Update and edit website content, posts and pages.
- Test and give feedback on new and existing technologies.

01. 2018-12. 2022

Architect

R+Y Projects, Lagos, Nigeria

- Created, printed and modified drawings in AutoCAD and Revit.
- Coordinated with segment leaders to promote architectural goals and design concepts.
- Consulted with clients to determine functionaland spatial requirements of new structure.
- Calculated cost estimates for smaller to larger projects.

Education

| 01. 2023- | Responsive Web Design Course Free Code Camp |
|------------------|---|
| 2019 - 2022 | Bachelor of Architecture, B.Arch Bells University of Technology |
| 2012- 2018 | Higher National Diploma Federal polytechnic Auchi. |